{"question": "On the morning of 18 September 2014, police in Australia carried out the biggest counter-terrorism operation in the nation's history, with over 800 heavily armed officers targeting households in the cities", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Miss Universe Thailand 2014, the 15th Miss Universe Thailand pageant was held at Royal Paragon Hall, Siam Paragon in Bangkok on May 17, 2014. The contestants camped in Roi Et. before", "answer": "flying"}
{"question": "The 2014 Farafra ambush (also called 2014 Al-Wadi Al-Gedid attack) occurred on 19 July 2014 when unidentified gunmen ambushed a desert checkpoint in the Farafra Oasis Road in Egypt's New Valley", "answer": "Governorate."}
{"question": "The 2014 Brisbane hailstorm struck Brisbane, the capital city of Queensland, Australia on 27 November 2014. The storm caused severe damage to many buildings and cars in the city. Around 40", "answer": "people"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Costa Rica on Sunday, 2 February 2014 to elect a new president, two vice presidents, and 57 Legislative Assembly lawmakers. In accordance with Article 132 of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2014 World Team Table Tennis Championships were held in Tokyo from 28 April to 5 May 2014. The Championships was staged in Japan for the seventh time and was the", "answer": "52nd"}
{"question": "The 15th Annual British Academy Television Craft Awards were presented by the British Academy of Film and Television Arts (BAFTA) on 24 April 2014, with Stephen Mangan presiding over the event.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "Operation Car Wash (Portuguese: Operação Lava Jato) was a criminal investigation by the Federal Police of Brazil's Curitiba branch. It began in March 2014 and was initially headed by investigative judge", "answer": "Sérgio"}
{"question": "Election to the 6th convocation of the Moscow City Duma took place on the United Voting Day on September 14, 2014. The elections were held in full by the majority system,", "answer": "45"}
{"question": "On 4 September 2014, 82-year-old Palmira Silva was beheaded in her back garden in Edmonton, London, by 25-year-old Nicholas Salvador, who was on a rampage. Friends of Salvador had recently noticed", "answer": "odd"}
{"question": "The Annot derailment occurred on 8 February 2014 when a train travelling from Nice to Digne-les-Bains on the Chemins de Fer de Provence was hit by a rock which fell down", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "Breck David Lafave Bednar (17 March 1999 – 17 February 2014) was an English teenager of American descent from Caterham, Surrey, who was murdered by 18-year-old Lewis Daynes on 17 February", "answer": "2014,"}
{"question": "The 2014 Vrancea earthquake struck Vrancea County on 22 November 2014 at 21:14:17 local time, with a moment magnitude of 5.7. The earthquake occurred at a depth of 39 kilometers and", "answer": "lasted"}
{"question": "Typhoon Hagupit (hə-goo-PEET, [hɐguˈpit]; Filipino word meaning \"lashing or flogging\"), known in the Philippines as Typhoon Ruby, was the second most intense tropical cyclone in 2014. Hagupit particularly impacted the Philippines", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Talking Statues is a project created initially in 2013 by David Peter Fox in Copenhagen, Denmark involving pre-recorded voiceovers accompanying various statues available in a smartphone app. The statue of Hans", "answer": "Christian"}
{"question": "The South Yorkshire Police and Crime Commissioner by-election was a 2014 by-election on 30 October 2014 for the position of Police and Crime Commissioner in the South Yorkshire Police region of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in the Central African Republic (also called MINUSCA, which is an initialism of its French name Mission multidimensionnelle intégrée des Nations unies pour la stabilisation", "answer": "en"}
{"question": "The Heywood and Middleton by-election was on 9 October 2014 in the Heywood and Middleton constituency following the death of its MP Jim Dobbin on 6 September 2014. It was held", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Antigua and Barbuda on 12 June 2014. The result was a victory for the opposition Antigua and Barbuda Labour Party led by Gaston Browne, which won", "answer": "14"}
{"question": "Miss International 2014, the 54th Miss International pageant, organized by the International Cultural Association held on November 11, 2014 at the Grand Prince Hotel Takanawa in Tokyo, Japan. Bea Santiago of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Kasta Tomb (Greek: Τύμβος Καστά), also known as the Amphipolis Tomb (Greek: Τάφος της Αμφίπολης), is the largest ancient tumulus (burial mound) ever discovered in Greece, and by comparison dwarfs", "answer": "that"}
{"question": "Patagotitan is a genus of titanosaurian sauropod dinosaur from the Cerro Barcino Formation in Chubut Province, Patagonia, Argentina. The genus contains a single species known from at least six young adult", "answer": "individuals,"}
{"question": "Eleanor Poppy Miranda de Freitas (26 June 1990 – 4 April 2014) was an English woman who committed suicide three days before the commencement of her trial for perverting the course", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2014 Tokyo Marathon (Japanese: 東京マラソン 2014) was the eighth edition of the annual marathon race in Tokyo, Japan and was held on Sunday, 23 February. An IAAF Gold Label Road", "answer": "Race,"}
{"question": "The 2014 unrest in Bosnia and Herzegovina was a series of demonstrations and riots that began in the northern town of Tuzla on 4 February 2014 but quickly spread to multiple", "answer": "cities"}
{"question": "The Local Audit and Accountability Act 2014 is a United Kingdom act of parliament. Its main provisions: abolish the Audit Commission and repeal the Audit Commission Act 1998 (section 1) establish", "answer": "new"}
{"question": "Clashes on the Armenian–Azerbaijan border (Tavush–Qazakh) and the line of contact between the Nagorno-Karabakh and Azerbaijan started on 27 July 2014. Reported casualties of the clashes were some of the highest", "answer": "since"}
{"question": "2014 Kunar Offensive refers to a 2014 armed conflict of the War in Afghanistan, between the Afghan Army and a terrorist group, Tehrik-i-Taliban Pakistan (TTP). It occurred in the Dangam district", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Fantastica Mania 2014 was a series of five professional wrestling events co-produced by Japanese promotion New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW) and Mexican promotion Consejo Mundial de Lucha Libre (CMLL) taking place between", "answer": "January"}
{"question": "Cyclone Christina was a European windstorm which caused three fatalities and €375 million in damage across western Europe in early January 2014, making landfall several days after Cyclone Anne. Forming out", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2015 World Junior Ice Hockey Championships was the 39th edition of Ice Hockey World Junior Championship, played from December 26, 2014 to January 5, 2015. It was co-hosted by Toronto,", "answer": "Ontario,"}
{"question": "Early general elections were held in Greenland on 28 November 2014. They were called after Prime Minister Aleqa Hammond resigned following a spending scandal. Siumut and Inuit Ataqatigiit emerged as the", "answer": "largest"}
{"question": "Around midday on October 22, 2014, a passing motorist saw an Asian woman walking north along the Ingraham Trail on the outskirts of Yellowknife in the Northwest Territories, Canada. Several days", "answer": "later,"}
{"question": "The 40th G7 summit was held 4–5 June, 2014 in Brussels, Belgium. It was originally scheduled to be held as the “40th G8 summit” and be hosted by Russia in the", "answer": "Black"}
{"question": "Miss France 2015, the 85th edition of the Miss France pageant, was held on December 6, 2014 at Zénith d'Orléans in Orléans. Miss France 2014, Flora Coquerel of Orléanais (Centre-Val de", "answer": "Loire)"}
{"question": "On 15 May 2014, the double-decker ferry MV Miraj-4 capsized in the Meghna River, 50 kilometres (31 mi) southeast of Dhaka, Bangladesh. Between 150 and 200 people were on board at", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The First Cabinet of Kim Kielsen was a former administration of Greenland. It was appointed on 10 December 2014 with Kim Kielsen from Forward (Siumut) as Prime Minister, leading a coalition", "answer": "between"}
{"question": "The March 2014 nor'easter was an extremely powerful extratropical cyclone that affected much of U.S. Gulf Coast, the eastern United States, eastern Canada, and Greenland. It was the most powerful winter", "answer": "storm"}
{"question": "The 2014 Channel O Music Video Awards took place on 29 November 2014 at the Nasrec Expo Centre in Soweto. Nominees were announced on 4 September. Cassper Nyovest, K.O and Davido", "answer": "led"}
{"question": "The 28th Goya Awards were presented at the Madrid Marriott Auditorium Hotel in Madrid on February 9, 2014 to honour the best in Spanish films of 2013. Manel Fuentes was the", "answer": "master"}
{"question": "Dzhumaya Mosque (Bulgarian: Джумая джамия) is located in Plovdiv, Plovdiv Province, Bulgaria. Its Turkish name is Hüdavendigâr Camii or Cuma Camii. The mosque is located in the centre of Plovdiv and", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "On 30 June or 2 July 2014, the Armed Forces of the Democratic Republic of the Congo and United Nations forces launched an offensive against rebel groups in the Masisi and", "answer": "Walikale"}
{"question": "The second inauguration of Juan Manuel Santos as the 32rd President of Colombia marked the beginning of his second term in the house of Nariño as head of state for Juan", "answer": "Manuel"}
{"question": "The ANZAC centenary advisory board was established by Department of the Prime Minister and Cabinet of Australia to organise the centenary commemorations of the Australian and jointly New Zealand contribution to", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2014 Moscow Victory Day Parade took place in Red Square on 9 May 2014 to commemorate the 69th anniversary of the capitulation of Nazi Germany in 1945, which formally ended", "answer": "hostilities"}
{"question": "The 2013–14 season was Galatasaray's 110th in existence and 56th consecutive season in the Süper Lig. The club was aiming for an unprecedented twentieth league title, after winning the Süper Lig", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Double salary saga is the name given by media outlets to a political scandal in Ghana. Between 2012 and 2016, some members of the John Dramani Mahama administration who were ministers", "answer": "or"}
{"question": "During the ongoing Russo-Ukrainian War between the Ukrainian government forces and pro-Russian separatists in the Donbas region of Ukraine that began in April 2014, many international organisations and states noted a", "answer": "deteriorating"}
{"question": "The 2014 Coupe de France Final decided the winner of the 2013–14 Coupe de France, the 97th season of France's premier football cup. It was played on 3 May at the", "answer": "Stade"}
{"question": "The Argentine debt restructuring is a process of debt restructuring by Argentina that began on January 14, 2005, and allowed it to resume payment on 76% of the US$82 billion in", "answer": "sovereign"}
{"question": "The centenary of the outbreak of World War I was commemorated in Europe in late July and early August 2014. A century earlier, the July Crisis, which occurred after the assassination", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2014 Paris Municipal elections took place on 23 and 30 March 2014, at the same time as other French municipal elections. Anne Hidalgo of the Socialist Party was elected mayor", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2014 Mexico–Guatemala earthquake struck 4 km (2.5 mi) west of Puerto Madero on July 7 at 05:23:54. The shock had a moment magnitude of 6.9 and a maximum Mercalli intensity", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2014 European Aquatics Championships took place from 13 to 24 August 2014 in Berlin, Germany. It was the 31st edition of the championships, and was held in a temporary facility", "answer": "placed"}
{"question": "The 2014 Coupe de la Ligue Final was the 20th final of France's football league cup competition, the Coupe de la Ligue, a competition for the 42 teams that the Ligue", "answer": "de"}
{"question": "A photograph of then-Labour Party leader Ed Miliband eating a bacon sandwich became a source of sustained commentary and the subject of an internet meme in 2014 and 2015. Taken for", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2014 Nuclear Security Summit was a summit held in The Hague, the Netherlands, on March 24 and 25, 2014. It was the third edition of the conference, succeeding the 2012", "answer": "Nuclear"}
{"question": "Before the Dawn was a concert residency by the English singer-songwriter Kate Bush in 2014 at the Hammersmith Apollo in London. The residency consisted of 22 dates; it was Bush's first", "answer": "series"}
{"question": "The Apollo of Gaza is a rare bronze sculpture of the Ancient Greek god Apollo found in the Gaza Strip in 2013. It was put for sale on eBay, and subsequently", "answer": "withdrawn"}
{"question": "Former Israeli Prime Minister Ariel Sharon died on 11 January 2014. His death received a number of international responses. His state funeral was held on 13 January in accordance with Jewish", "answer": "burial"}
{"question": "The Canada–Korea Free Trade Agreement (CKFTA; less often known as CSKFTA - Canada-South Korea Free Trade Agreement) is a free trade agreement between Canada and South Korea. The agreement was concluded", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "Elections for the Legislature of Guam took place on November 4, 2014, coinciding with the 2014 United States elections and the Guam gubernatorial election. All 15 seats in the Legislature of", "answer": "Guam"}
{"question": "The Minsk agreements were a series of international agreements which sought to end the Donbas war fought between armed Russian separatist groups and Armed Forces of Ukraine, with Russian regular forces", "answer": "playing"}
{"question": "Ryōgoku Peter Pan 2014: Maybe Summer Will Change My Life! (両国ピーターパン2014〜人生変えちゃう夏かもね!〜, Ryōgoku Pītā Pan 2014: jinsei kaechau natsu kamo ne) was a professional wrestling event promoted by DDT Pro-Wrestling (DDT). The", "answer": "event"}
{"question": "Tapela and Another v Attorney General and Others is a legal case in Botswana concerning the right of two HIV-positive non-citizen prisoners to access antiretroviral (ARV) medication at state expense. On", "answer": "22"}
{"question": "Presidential elections were held in Algeria on 17 April 2014. Incumbent President Abdelaziz Bouteflika was re-elected with 82% of the vote. Issues in the campaign included a desire for domestic stability", "answer": "after"}
{"question": "Wrestle Kingdom 8 in Tokyo Dome was a professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) event produced by the New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW) promotion, which took place at the Tokyo Dome in Tokyo, Japan", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The Pocklington Iron Age burial ground is a prehistoric cemetery discovered in 2014 on the outskirts of Pocklington in the East Riding of Yorkshire, England. Excavations carried out on an ongoing", "answer": "basis"}
{"question": "On 18 May 2014, a bus carrying 49 passengers caught on fire in Fundación, Colombia. According to different sources, 32 children, 33 children or 31 children and one adult died as", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "An internal conflict in the Central African Republic (CAR) started essentially on 13 April 2013, when the government of President Michel Djotodia officially took over. The fighting was between the government", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Operation Okra is the Australian Defence Force (ADF) contribution to the military intervention against the Islamic State. The force is part of Joint Task Force 633 in the Middle East. The", "answer": "operation"}
{"question": "The Miss Brazil 2014 was the 60th edition of the Miss Brazil pageant, held in Centro de Eventos do Ceará, Fortaleza, Ceará, Jakelyne Oliveira of Mato Grosso, crowned her successor Melissa", "answer": "Gurgel"}
{"question": "The 2014 Tokyo gubernatorial election took place on February 9, 2014 to replace outgoing Governor Naoki Inose, who resigned effective December 24, 2013. Yōichi Masuzoe was declared the winner in exit", "answer": "polling,"}
{"question": "The 2013–14 Burkinabé Premier League is the 52nd edition of top flight football in Burkina Faso. A total of sixteen teams competed in the season beginning on 7 December 2013 and", "answer": "ending"}
{"question": "In 2014, two explosions of ammunition depots occurred in Vrbětice of Vlachovice) in the Zlín District of the Czech Republic. The first explosion occurred on 16 October, and the second on", "answer": "3"}
{"question": "The Economic Adjustment Programme for Cyprus, usually referred to as the Bailout programme, is a memorandum of understanding on financial assistance to the Republic of Cyprus in order to cope with", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2014–15 North American winter was frigid and prolifically wintry, especially across the eastern half of North America in the months of January–March. The season began early, with many places in", "answer": "North"}
{"question": "The 2014 FIBA World Championship for Women, the 17th edition of FIBA's premier international tournament for women's national basketball teams, was held in Ankara and Istanbul, Turkey from 27 September to", "answer": "5"}
{"question": "R v Incedal and Rarmoul-Bouhadjar (2014), formerly known as R v AB and CD, is a criminal case brought in the United Kingdom against two people suspected of terrorism offences. It", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "The Estación Polar Científica Conjunta Glaciar Unión (or Union Glacier Joint Scientific Polar Station) or Union Glacier Station is a summer Antarctic base of Chile, situated on Union Glacier in the", "answer": "Ellsworth"}
{"question": "The Chinese Golf Factory Workers Strike for Essential Rights was a strike that happened in Shenzhen, China. On July 21, 2014, approximately 300 Chinese workers at China Qilitian Golf Articles (QLT),", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Presidential elections were held in El Salvador on 2 February 2014, with a second round held on 9 March since no candidate won an outright majority. The primary candidates were Vice-President", "answer": "Salvador"}
{"question": "The 2014 Gorni Lom explosions were a series of explosions that began on the afternoon of October 1, 2014, at 16:59 pm local time at the former Midzhur Ammo Plant in", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Eurovision Debate is a live televised debate between the lead political candidates (“Spitzenkandidaten”) running to be the next President of the European Commission. Produced by the European Broadcasting Union (EBU)", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "Atiqullah Raufi was the chief of the secretariat of the Supreme Court of Afghanistan. He was assassinated as he was heading to work on December 13, 2014, around 9:00 a.m., in", "answer": "Kabul,"}
{"question": "The General Debate of the sixty-ninth session of the United Nations General Assembly commenced on 24 September 2014 and ended on 1 October 2014. Leaders from a number of member states", "answer": "addressed"}
{"question": "The Vienna Summer of Logic was a scientific event in the summer of 2014, combining 12 major conferences and several workshops from the fields of mathematical logic, logic in computer science,", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The Hampden Bridge was a heritage-listed wooden Allan Truss bridge over the Murrumbidgee River in Wagga Wagga, in New South Wales, Australia. It was officially opened to traffic on 11 November", "answer": "1895"}
{"question": "2013–2014 Satkhira clashes refers to the crackdown on killed in a joint operations by Border Guards Bangladesh, Rapid Action Battalion and Bangladesh police in different places of Satkhira district, Bangladesh during", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Miss Universo Chile 2014, the 51st Miss Universo Chile pageant, was held on December 8, 2014. María Jesús Matthei crowned Hellen Toncio as her successor at end of the event. Hellen", "answer": "will"}
{"question": "On January 17, 2014, a suicide bomber detonated explosives at the gate of the Taverna du Liban, a heavily fortified restaurant in Kabul popular with foreign nationals, including diplomats, aid workers", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "Azerbaijan participated in the Eurovision Song Contest 2014 with the song \"Start a Fire\" written by Stefan Örn, Johan Kronlund and Alessandra Günthardt. The song was performed by Dilara Kazimova. The", "answer": "Azerbaijani"}
{"question": "Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 (MH370/MAS370) was an international passenger flight operated by Malaysia Airlines that disappeared on 8 March 2014 while flying from Kuala Lumpur International Airport in Malaysia to its", "answer": "planned"}
{"question": "Lars Joachim Mittank (born February 9, 1986) is a German man who disappeared on July 8, 2014, near Varna Airport in Varna, Bulgaria. Mittank was vacationing at the Golden Sands resort,", "answer": "where"}
{"question": "In October 2013, there was an outbreak of Zika fever in French Polynesia, the first outbreak of several Zika outbreaks across Oceania. With 8,723 cases reported, it was the largest outbreak", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Air Algérie Flight 5017 was a scheduled international passenger flight from Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso, to Algiers, Algeria, which crashed near Gossi, Mali, on 24 July 2014. The McDonnell Douglas MD-83 twinjet", "answer": "with"}
{"question": "Miss Colombia 2014 was the 62nd edition of the Miss Colombia pageant. It was held on November 17, 2014 in Cartagena, Colombia. At the end of the event, Paulina Vega of", "answer": "Atlántico"}
{"question": "On 15 July 2014, at around 8:40 am MSK (UTC+04:00), an outbound Moscow Metro train derailed between Park Pobedy and Slavyansky Bulvar stations of the Arbatsko-Pokrovskaya Line. Casualties reported include 24", "answer": "dead"}
{"question": "The 67th British Academy Film Awards, more commonly known as the BAFTAs, were held on 16 February 2014 at the Royal Opera House in London, honouring the best national and foreign", "answer": "films"}
{"question": "On 2 May 2014, a pair of mudslides occurred in Argo District, Badakhshan Province, Afghanistan. The death toll is uncertain, the number of deaths varying from 350 to 2,700. Around 300", "answer": "houses"}
{"question": "The Exempted Limited Partnership Law, 2014 (Law 5 of 2014) is a statute of the Cayman Islands. It was passed on 2 July 2014. Section 50 of the Law repeals the", "answer": "Exempted"}
{"question": "A joint declaration was made on 11 February 2014 at the start of renewed negotiations to settle the Cyprus dispute. The following talks between Nicos Anastasiades, President of Cyprus, and Derviş", "answer": "Eroğlu,"}
{"question": "Water supply problems in Caleta Olivia occurred on 2014 (called the Thirst Days) and culminated in a series of protests about the lack of water produced by the rupture of the", "answer": "aqueduct"}
{"question": "On June 19, 2014, torrential rains caused severe flash flooding across northeastern Bulgaria leaving dozens of villages without electricity and submerging large parts of several cities in the region. At least", "answer": "16"}
{"question": "Gutter oil, trench oil, sewer oil and tainted oil (Chinese: 地沟油 / 地溝油; pinyin: dìgōu yóu, or 餿水油; sōushuǐ yóu) are Chinese slang terms primarily used in China and Taiwan to", "answer": "refer"}
{"question": "On December 29, 2013, three journalists working for the Qatari-based international news channel Al Jazeera English, Australian Peter Greste, Canadian Mohamed Fahmy and Egyptian Baher Mohamed were taken into custody by", "answer": "Egyptian"}
{"question": "On August 12, 2014 a magnitude 5.1 earthquake struck Ecuador 22 km (14 mi) west-southwest of Cayambe at a depth of 11.9 km (7.4 mi). The earthquake shook Ecuador's capital Quito", "answer": "32"}
{"question": "The 2014 Georgian local elections (Georgian: საქართველოს ადგილობრივი თვითმმართველობის ორგანოების არჩევნები) were held on 15 June and 12 July 2014 to elect the councils of local government, sakrebulo, mayors of 12", "answer": "self-governing"}
{"question": "Gubernatorial elections were held in the Democratic Republic of the Congo in March 2014. The elections were initially scheduled for 2012, but were delayed until 2014.Elections were held for nineteen provincial", "answer": "governors."}
{"question": "The Indian consulate in Herat, Afghanistan was attacked on 23 May 2014 by four heavily armed militants, three days before the inaugural ceremony of Narendra Modi as the Prime Minister of", "answer": "India."}
{"question": "Organizations from around the world responded to the West African Ebola virus epidemic. In July 2014, the World Health Organization (WHO) convened an emergency meeting with health ministers from eleven countries", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The eighteenth summit of 'South Asian Association of Regional Cooperation' (SAARC) was held in Kathmandu, the capital of Federal Democratic Republic of Nepal during 26–27 November 2014. The theme of the", "answer": "summit"}
{"question": "Cyprus selected their Junior Eurovision Song Contest 2014 entry through an internal selection. On 21 July 2014 it was revealed that Sophia Patsalides would represent Cyprus in the contest with the", "answer": "song"}
{"question": "The 31st Robert Awards ceremony was held on 26 February 2014 in Copenhagen, Denmark. Organized by the Danish Film Academy, the awards honoured the best in Danish and foreign film of", "answer": "2013."}
{"question": "The 2014 Pentecost weekend storms in Europe were a series of intense supercells and MCSs affecting western and central Europe, which followed a heatwave in early June 2014, resulting from a", "answer": "Spanish"}
{"question": "An earthquake occurred in the northern Aegean Sea between Greece and Turkey on May 24, 2014. It had a moment magnitude of 6.9 and a maximum Mercalli intensity of VIII (Severe).", "answer": "Serious"}
{"question": "On 24 November 2013, the Joint Plan of Action (برنامه اقدام مشترک), also known as the Geneva interim agreement (Persian: توافق هسته‌ای ژنو), was a pact signed between Iran and the", "answer": "P5+1"}
{"question": "On 3 October 2014, Canadian Prime Minister Stephen Harper announced that he would put forth a motion to send forces to participate in the coalition for military intervention against ISIL by", "answer": "deploying"}
{"question": "In July 2014, an internationally publicised incident occurred in which a Thai woman, Pattaramon Janbua, who had been hired as a surrogate mother for an Australian couple, sought to raise money", "answer": "for"}
{"question": "Miss Brazil World 2014 was the 25th edition of the Miss Brazil World pageant and the 9th under MMB Productions & Events. The contest took place on August 9, 2014. Each", "answer": "state,"}
{"question": "The 2014 Open GDF Suez was a women's professional tennis tournament played on indoor hardcourts. It was the 22nd edition of the Open GDF Suez (formerly known as the Open Gaz", "answer": "de"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Bolivia on 12 October 2014, the second to take place under the country's 2009 constitution, and the first supervised by the Plurinational Electoral Organ, a newly", "answer": "created"}
{"question": "The 2014 G20 Brisbane summit was the ninth meeting of the G20 heads of government/heads of state. It was held in Brisbane, the capital city of Queensland, Australia, on 15–16 November", "answer": "2014."}
{"question": "Hamas, the governing authority in the Gaza Strip, has constructed a sophisticated network of military tunnels since it seized control of the Strip in 2007. The tunnel system branches beneath many", "answer": "Gazan"}
{"question": "Julieka Ivanna Dhu (commonly referred to as Ms Dhu; her first name was generally not used in media reports out of respect for Aboriginal naming customs) was a 22-year-old Aboriginal Australian", "answer": "woman"}
{"question": "The African Declaration on Internet Rights and Freedoms (AfDec) has been created in order to promote an Internet environment that conforms to established human rights standards and meets Africa's social and", "answer": "economic"}
{"question": "Presidential elections were held in Croatia on 28 December 2014 and 11 January 2015, the sixth such elections since independence in 1991. Only four candidates contested the elections, the lowest number", "answer": "since"}
{"question": "On October 11, 2014, Jennifer Laude (Tagalog pronunciation: [ˈlaʊdɛ]), a Filipina trans woman, was drowned to death by Joseph Scott Pemberton, a Lance Corporal in the United States Marine Corps in", "answer": "Olongapo,"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Botswana on 24 October 2014. The result was an eleventh straight victory for the Botswana Democratic Party, which won 37 of the 57 elected seats. Incumbent", "answer": "President"}
{"question": "The International Year of Crystallography (abbreviation: IYCr2014) is an event promoted in the year 2014 by the United Nations to celebrate the centenary of the discovery of X-ray crystallography and to", "answer": "emphasise"}
{"question": "S.A.S. v. France was a case brought for the European Court of Human Rights which ruled that the French ban on face covering did not violate European Convention on Human Rights's", "answer": "(ECHR)"}
{"question": "King of Pro-Wrestling (2014) was a professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) event promoted by New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW). The event took place on October 13, 2014, in Tokyo at Ryōgoku Kokugikan and", "answer": "featured"}
{"question": "The Ettehadiya case is a controversial legal case in Egypt where thousands of protesters went down to the Ittihadiya Palace, the Presidential offices in Cairo, asking for the repeal of the", "answer": "newly"}
{"question": "Alice Gross (14 February 2000 – 28 August 2014) was an English girl who was murdered in West London. Her body was found hidden on the bed of the River Brent", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The 2014 European Individual Chess Championship took place from 2 to 15 March in Yerevan. 263 players took part. Although sometimes described as the men's championship, several women took part, including", "answer": "Judit"}
{"question": "The 2014 Split district elections were held on 9 June 2014 for the councils of 34 city districts and local committees of Split. The Croatian Democratic Union coalition won 98 council", "answer": "seats,"}
{"question": "The Cemfjord was a Cyprus-registered cargo ship which foundered in the Pentland Firth off the north-east coast of Scotland on 2 January 2015. Built as the general cargo ship Margareta in", "answer": "1984,"}
{"question": "Cyclone Tini (also referred to as Storm Darwin in Ireland) a European windstorm that Western Europe, particularly Ireland and the United Kingdom on 12 February 2014. The storm brought hurricane-force winds", "answer": "to"}
{"question": "José Salvador Alvarenga (Spanish: [xoˈse salβaˈðoɾ alβaˈɾeŋɡa]; born c. 1975) is a Salvadoran fisherman and author who was found on January 30, 2014, aged 36 or 37, on the Marshall Islands", "answer": "after"}
{"question": "The 2014 SCO summit was the 13th annual summit of heads of state of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation held between 11 and 12 September in Dushanbe, Tajikistan. Security was among the", "answer": "top"}
{"question": "Presidential elections were held in Colombia on 25 May 2014. Since no candidate received 50% of the vote in the first round, a run-off between the two candidates with the most", "answer": "votes"}
{"question": "The 6th BRICS summit was the sixth annual diplomatic meeting of the BRICS, a grouping of major emerging economies that includes Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa. It was hosted", "answer": "by"}
{"question": "Chang'e 5-T1 (Chinese: 嫦娥五号T1; pinyin: Cháng'é wǔhào T1) was an experimental robotic spacecraft that was launched to the Moon on 23 October 2014, by the China National Space Administration (CNSA) to", "answer": "conduct"}
{"question": "The analysis of communications between Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 and Inmarsat's satellite telecommunication network provide the primary source of information about Flight 370's location and possible in-flight events after it disappeared", "answer": "from"}
{"question": "Bulgaria selected their Junior Eurovision Song Contest 2014 entry through an internal selection. On 26 July 2014 the Bulgarian broadcaster BNT stated that they will return to the contest with Krisia", "answer": "Todorova."}
{"question": "2013–2014 Atlantic winter storms in Europe were a series of winter storms affecting areas of Atlantic Europe and beyond. The French Atlantic coastal regions (chiefly Brittany), South West and Southern England,", "answer": "West"}
{"question": "The impact of the Arab Spring concerns protests or by the way attempts to organize growing protest movements that were inspired by or similar to the Arab Spring in the Arab-majority", "answer": "states"}
{"question": "Cayman has introduced a new regime for the licensing and registration of directors of investment fund companies that are “regulated” under the Mutual Funds Law (2013 Revision) and directors of companies", "answer": "registered"}
{"question": "The United States–Africa Leaders Summit 2014 was an international summit held in Washington D.C. from August 4–6, 2014. Leaders from fifty African states attended the three-day summit, which was hosted by", "answer": "U.S."}
{"question": "Ethiopian Airlines Flight 702 was a scheduled flight from Addis Ababa to Milan via Rome on 17 February 2014. The aircraft, an Ethiopian Airlines Boeing 767-300ER, was hijacked by the unarmed", "answer": "co-pilot,"}
{"question": "The Muslim Youth uprising is the official name given to an unsuccessful \"Islamic revolution\" that was set to take place in Egypt on November 28, 2014. The Salafist Front, an Islamist", "answer": "organization"}
{"question": "The 39th annual Toronto International Film Festival, the 39th event in the Toronto International Film Festival series, was held in Canada from 4–14 September 2014. David Dobkin's film The Judge, starring", "answer": "Robert"}
{"question": "The 2014 Yingjiang earthquake occurred on 24 May at 4:49 a.m. local time in Yingjiang County, Yunnan Province, China, with a moment magnitude of 5.6 and a maximum perceived intensity of", "answer": "VII"}
{"question": "The 19th National Television Awards was held at The O2 Arena on 22 January 2014. The event was presented by Dermot O'Leary, who himself was nominated for an award. The ceremony", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "The Aswan tribal clashes were a series of clashes east of Egypt's southern city of Aswan between two local ethnic tribes: the Arab Al-Halayel (Beni Helal) clan and the Nubian Al-Dabodeya", "answer": "family."}
{"question": "ARSAT-1 is a geostationary communications satellite operated by AR-SAT and built by the Argentine company INVAP. ARSAT-1 was launched into orbit on October 16, 2014, from French Guiana alongside Intelsat-30 satellite", "answer": "using"}
{"question": "Parliamentary elections were held in Colombia on 9 March 2014 to elect members to both chambers of Congress. The nationwide constituency for the 102-member Senate was contested, as well as the", "answer": "166"}
{"question": "From July 8 to August 26, 2014, another conflict between Israel and Gaza escalated and led to the outbreak of a war between Israel and Gaza. Between 2,127- 2,168 Gazans were", "answer": "killed,"}
{"question": "Arturo (1985 – July 3, 2016) was a polar bear living in Mendoza Zoological Park in Mendoza, Argentina, the only polar bear living in the country. He was born in the", "answer": "United"}
{"question": "The 2014–15 Linafoot season (known as the Vodacom Superligue 2014–15 for sponsorship reasons) is the 54th since its establishment. It began on 4 October 2014. A total of 20 clubs participate", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Presidential elections were held in Egypt between 26 and 28 May 2014. There were only two candidates, former Egyptian defence minister Abdel Fattah el-Sisi and Egyptian Popular Current candidate Hamdeen Sabahi.", "answer": "El-Sisi"}
{"question": "A by-election was held on 20 November 2014 for the UK parliamentary constituency of Rochester and Strood in Kent, England. The sitting Member of Parliament (MP) Mark Reckless called it on", "answer": "joining"}
{"question": "Below are the foreign reactions to the Euromaidan. Euromaidan was a wave of demonstrations and civil unrest in Ukraine that began on the night of 21 November 2013 after the Ukrainian", "answer": "government"}
{"question": "Croatia selected their Junior Eurovision Song Contest 2014 entry through an internal selection. On 2 October 2014 it was revealed that Josephine Zec would represent Croatia in the contest with the", "answer": "song"}
{"question": "The 2014 Helsinki University massacre plan was a mass murder planned by two people in Helsinki, Finland. The plan was discovered in spring 2014. The attack never happened, because a third", "answer": "person"}
{"question": "The 67th Bodil Awards were held on 1 February 2014 in the Bremen Theater in Copenhagen, Denmark, honouring the best national and foreign films of 2013. The Hunt won the award", "answer": "for"}
{"question": "The Yarkand Massacre was an episode of violence that began on 28 July 2014 in Yarkant County, Kashgar Region of the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region, China, and lasted for several days,", "answer": "as"}
{"question": "Between the months of March and April 2014, a court in Minya, Egypt, has recommended the death sentence to hundreds of members and supporters of the banned Muslim Brotherhood over an", "answer": "attack"}
{"question": "Georgia participated in the Junior Eurovision Song Contest 2014 which took place on 15 November 2014, in Marsa, Malta. Georgian Public Broadcaster (GPB) was responsible for organising their entry for the", "answer": "contest."}
{"question": "Many states and international organisations have reacted to the ongoing Russo-Ukrainian War in the Donbas region of Ukraine, which began in April 2014. In August 2014 when the intervention of Russian", "answer": "troops"}
{"question": "The 36th Moscow International Film Festival took place from 19 to 28 June 2014. Russian film director Gleb Panfilov was the head of the main jury. Gabe Polsky's Red Army was", "answer": "selected"}
{"question": "The 2014–15 Burkinabé Premier League is the 53rd edition of top flight football in Burkina Faso. A total of sixteen teams competed in the season beginning on 25 October 2014 and", "answer": "ending"}
{"question": "Queen + Adam Lambert Rock Big Ben Live was a concert on New Year's Eve 2014 and New Years Day 2015 performed by Queen + Adam Lambert to celebrate the New", "answer": "Year"}
{"question": "G 1/13 is a decision issued on 25 November 2014 by the Enlarged Board of Appeal of the European Patent Office (EPO), holding that in opposition proceedings a retroactive effect of", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "Simon Hall (1977 or 1978 – 23 February 2014) was a British murderer who was wrongly helped by 'miscarriage of justice' campaigners, only for him to go on to confess to", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Miss World 2014, the 64th edition of the Miss World pageant, was held on 14 December 2014 at the ExCeL London in London, United Kingdom. 121 contestants competed for the crown.", "answer": "Megan"}
{"question": "General elections were held in the Republika Srpska entity of Bosnia and Herzegovina on 12 October 2014 as part of the Bosnian general elections. Incumbent President Milorad Dodik was re-elected, running", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The Hai Yang Shi You 981 standoff, also known as the 2014 China-Vietnam oil rig crisis, refers to the tensions between China and Vietnam arising from the Chinese state-owned China National", "answer": "Offshore"}
{"question": "The 2014 Gaza War, also known as Operation Protective Edge (Hebrew: מִבְצָע צוּק אֵיתָן, romanized: Miv'tza Tzuk Eitan, lit. 'Operation Strong Cliff'), was a military operation launched by Israel on 8", "answer": "July"}
{"question": "The 14th Cook Islands Parliament is the previous term of the Parliament of the Cook Islands. Its composition was determined by the 2014 elections on 9 July 2014.Due to an election-night", "answer": "tie"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Dominica on 8 December 2014 to elect the 21 members of the House of Assembly. Prime Minister Roosevelt Skerrit announced the election date on 5 November", "answer": "2014"}
{"question": "The Delhi-Kathmandu bus is a trans-boundary bus service connecting India and Nepal's capitals at Delhi and Kathmandu respectively. The service is operated by the Delhi Transport Corporation (DTC) and was launched", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Belarus participated in the Junior Eurovision Song Contest 2014 in Marsa, Malta. The Belarusian entry was selected through a national final, organised by Belarusian broadcaster National State Television and Radio Company", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The Newark by-election was a by-election in the Newark constituency of the British House of Commons, which was held on 5 June 2014, following the resignation of Patrick Mercer. Conservative Robert", "answer": "Jenrick"}
{"question": "The 2014 Toronto Argonauts season was their 57th season in the Canadian Football League and their 142nd season overall. The Argonauts finished in third place in the East Division but missed", "answer": "out"}
{"question": "The 2013–2014 Israeli–Palestinian peace talks were part of the Israeli–Palestinian peace process. Direct negotiations between Israel and the Palestinians began on 29 July 2013 following an attempt by United States Secretary", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Azerbaijan participated in the Turkvision Song Contest 2014 which took place in Kazan, Tatarstan, Russia. Azad Azerbaijan TV (ATV) was responsible for organising their entry for the contest. Elvin Ordubadli won", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The World Cultural Council performed its 31st Award Ceremony on November 17, 2014 at the Dipoli Hall, Otakaari 1 Building, Aalto University, Espoo, Finland. Aalto University acted as the host and", "answer": "co-organizer"}
{"question": "On 20 October 2014, Unijet Flight 074P, a Dassault Falcon 50 business jet taking off from Vnukovo International Airport in Moscow, Russia, crashed into a snow plow that had strayed onto", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Zhengzhou Airport riot occurred on 5–6 February 2014. Passengers at the airport in Zhengzhou, capital of the Chinese province of Henan, angry over lengthy delays due to snowy weather, smashed", "answer": "computers"}
{"question": "Anguilla competed in the 2014 Commonwealth Games in Glasgow, Scotland from July 23 to August 3, 2014. On June 30, 2014, Anguilla's final squad of 12 athletes in 2 sports was", "answer": "named."}
{"question": "The GSK China scandal was an imbroglio where the China branch of the global drugmaker GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) pleaded guilty to paying bribes to doctors and hospitals to promote the company's products", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "2014 Commonwealth of Independent States Cup was the 22nd annual Commonwealth of Independent States Cup since its establishment in 1993. It was hosted in Saint Petersburg, Russia between 24 January and", "answer": "2"}
{"question": "The 16th Meril Prothom Alo Awards ceremony, presented by Prothom Alo took place on 25 April 2014, at the Bangabandhu International Conference Center in Dhaka, Bangladesh as a part of 2013–14", "answer": "film"}
{"question": "Presidential elections were held in Afghanistan on 5 April 2014, with a second round held on 14 June. Incumbent President Hamid Karzai was not eligible to run due to term limits.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "The Flanders Fields Memorial Garden is a monument dedicated to the participants of World War I situated alongside the Guards Chapel at Wellington Barracks in Central London, England. The garden was", "answer": "opened"}
{"question": "The 2014 Toronto Blue Jays season was the 38th season for the franchise, and the 25th full season of play (26th overall) at Rogers Centre. Pitcher Roy Halladay signed a one-day", "answer": "contract"}
{"question": "The XX International AIDS Conference was held in Melbourne, Australia from 20 to 25 July 2014 at the Melbourne Convention and Exhibition Centre. It was organized by the International AIDS Society).", "answer": "Over"}
{"question": "On 22 April 2014, a freight train derailed near the Katongola Bridge in Haut-Lomami Province of the Democratic Republic of the Congo. The train was carrying hundreds of illegal passengers at", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Report of the Commission of Inquiry on Human Rights in the Democratic People's Republic of Korea is the landmark document resulting from the investigations on human rights in North Korea", "answer": "commissioned"}
{"question": "Spy Booth was an artwork by Banksy in Cheltenham, England. The piece has been seen as a critique of the global surveillance disclosures of 2013.In 2014, Robin Barton and Bankrobber London", "answer": "helped"}
{"question": "The Mini-Hollands scheme was introduced in March 2014 by Boris Johnson, then Mayor of London. It took the form of a competition among outer London boroughs for a £100-million fund. Three", "answer": "boroughs"}
{"question": "On the afternoon of 24 May 2014, a gunman opened fire at the Jewish Museum of Belgium in Brussels, killing four people. Three of them, an Israeli couple on holiday and", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "The Schellenberg smuggling incident is a case in which Canadian citizen Robert Lloyd Schellenberg was arrested, tried, and convicted on charges of smuggling drugs in the People's Republic of China. According", "answer": "to"}
{"question": "The Colombian peace process is the peace process between the Colombian government of President Juan Manuel Santos and the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC–EP) to bring an end to the", "answer": "Colombian"}
{"question": "A by-election was held in the Cook Islands constituency of Mitiaro on 11 November 2014.In the July 2014 general election, the contest for the Mitiaro seat resulted in a tie. Incumbent", "answer": "MP"}
{"question": "China–Brazil Earth Resources Satellite 4 (CBERS-4), also known as Ziyuan I-04 or Ziyuan 1E, is a remote sensing satellite intended for operation as part of the China–Brazil Earth Resources Satellite program", "answer": "between"}
{"question": "The Toronto Rock are a lacrosse team based in Toronto playing in the National Lacrosse League (NLL). The 2014 season was the 17th in franchise history, and 16th as the Rock.", "answer": "After"}
{"question": "Miss Teen USA 2014, the 32nd Miss Teen USA pageant. It was held at the Atlantis Paradise Island Resort in Nassau, Bahamas on August 2, 2014 and was hosted by Australian", "answer": "journalist"}
{"question": "Operation Full Disclosure (Hebrew: מבצע חשיפה מלאה) was a military operation carried out by the Israel Defense Forces on March 5, 2014, in the Red Sea. After days of surveillance far", "answer": "out"}
{"question": "EgyptSat 2 (also called MisrSat 2) was Egypt's second remote sensing Earth observation satellite. It was built by the Russian RSC Energia and the Egyptian NARSS while the incorporated cameras and", "answer": "payload"}
{"question": "In the year 2014, Ghana was hit with a scandal in the Police Service involving a top official in the person of DCOP Patrick Timbilla. On 6 March 2014, after the", "answer": "Independence"}
{"question": "Mercedes-Benz Fashion Week is an annual fashion industry event held in Sydney, Australia. The event is a part of Australian Fashion Week and has taken place at Carriageworks for two consecutive", "answer": "years."}
{"question": "International reactions to the annexation of Crimea by the Russian Federation have largely been condemnatory of Russia's actions, supportive of Ukraine's sovereignty and territorial integrity, and supportive of finding a quick", "answer": "end"}
{"question": "A by-election was held in the Cook Islands electorate of Murienua on 19 February 2014. The by-election was precipitated by the resignation of the winner of the 2013 Murienua by-election following", "answer": "allegations"}
{"question": "A referendum on joining the Unified Patent Court was held in Denmark on 25 May 2014 alongside European Parliament elections. The referendum was approved with 62.5% of the vote, enabling the", "answer": "government"}
{"question": "The Suez Canal Corridor Area Project (Arabic: مشروع تطوير محور قناة السويس) is a megaproject in Egypt that was launched on 5 August 2014 by President Abdel Fattah el-Sisi and completed", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The 2014 West Midlands Police and Crime Commissioner by-election was a by-election for the position of Police and Crime Commissioner in the West Midlands Police region of the United Kingdom, held", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "William Tyrrell (born 26 June 2011) is an Australian boy who disappeared at the age of three from Kendall, New South Wales, on 12 September 2014. He had been playing at", "answer": "his"}
{"question": "Protests against the 2013 Egyptian coup d'état erupted in July 2013. Immediately following the removal of President Mohamed Morsi by the Egyptian Armed Forces on 3 July 2013 amid demonstrations against", "answer": "Morsi's"}
{"question": "The BRW Rich 200, 2014 is the 31st annual survey of the wealthiest people resident in Australia, published online by The Australian Financial Review on 26 June 2014.In the 2014 list,", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 19th Empire Awards ceremony (officially known as the Jameson Empire Awards), presented by the British film magazine Empire, honored the best films of 2013 and took place on 30 March", "answer": "2014"}
{"question": "The Bristol child sex abuse ring was a group of 13 men who committed sexual offences against underage teenage girls in Bristol, in Southwestern England. In November 2014, they were convicted", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The concept of Targeted Poverty Alleviation (simplified Chinese: 精准扶贫; traditional Chinese:精準扶貧, pinyin: jīng zhǔn fú pín) was first raised by Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the Chinese Communist Party to combat", "answer": "poverty"}
{"question": "Stichting Shell Pensioenfonds v Krys [2014] UKPC 41 (24 November 2014) was a decision of the Privy Council on appeal from the British Virgin Islands relating to an anti-suit injunction in", "answer": "connection"}
{"question": "The Wold Newton Hoard is a coin hoard dating from the early 4th century AD. It contains 1,857 coins held within a pottery container. It was acquired by the Yorkshire Museum", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The 2014 National Coalition Party leadership election was held in Lahti, Finland on 14 June 2014 to elect the new chair of the National Coalition Party. Incumbent party chair and Prime", "answer": "Minister"}
{"question": "Forum for India-Pacific Islands cooperation (FIPIC) is a multinational grouping developed in 2014 for cooperation between India and 14 Pacific Islands nations which include Cook Islands, Fiji, Kiribati, Marshall Islands, Micronesia,", "answer": "Nauru,"}
{"question": "The 2014 Vorarlberg state election was held on 21 September 2014 to elect the members of the Landtag of Vorarlberg. The Austrian People's Party (ÖVP) suffered substantial losses, and was deprived", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2014 DFB-Pokal Final decided the winner of the 2013–14 DFB-Pokal, the 71st season of Germany's premier football cup. It was played on 17 May at the Olympiastadion in Berlin. In", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 45th Pacific Islands Forum was held from 29 July to 1 August 2014 in Palau. The forum's official opening was held in the capital Ngerulmud, in Melekeok State, but the", "answer": "majority"}
{"question": "On 23 June 2014, a German Eurofighter Typhoon fighter jet and a Learjet 35 business jet participating in a military exercise collided mid-air over Olsberg, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany. The Learjet subsequently", "answer": "crashed"}
{"question": "2014 Kalbajar incident refers to the crossing of a small group of Azerbaijanis into Kalbajar district, their subsequent capture and conviction for murder and sabotage by the Republic of Artsakh. In", "answer": "July"}
{"question": "The Brazilian Anti-Corruption Act (Brazilian Portuguese: Lei anticorrupção) officially \"Law No. 12,846\" and commonly known as the Clean Company Act (Lei da Empresa Limpa) is a Brazilian law enacted in 2014", "answer": "targeting"}
{"question": "Global Wars was a professional wrestling supershow co-produced by the American Ring of Honor (ROH) and Japanese New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW) promotions. The event took place on May 10, 2014, at", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Ninth East Asia Summit was held in Nay Pyi Taw, Myanmar (Burma) on November 12–14, 2014. The East Asia Summit is an annual meeting of national leaders from the East", "answer": "Asian"}
{"question": "The Arab Sharkas case is the name given to the military trial of nine men in Egypt in August 2014. Six defendants were sentenced to death in October, and executed in", "answer": "May"}
{"question": "In the afternoon of January 21, 2014, the Chinese internet suffered a major failure. The country's DNS infrastructure, which is responsible for translating domain names into IP addresses, started directing unrelated", "answer": "domains"}
{"question": "The Wythenshawe and Sale East by-election was a by-election held on 13 February 2014 for the Parliament of the United Kingdom's House of Commons constituency of Wythenshawe and Sale East, following", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "From mid-2014 onward, Brazil experienced a severe economic crisis. The country's Gross Domestic Product (GDP) fell by 3.5% in 2015 and 3.3% in 2016, after which a small economic recovery began.", "answer": "That"}
{"question": "25 Churchill Place is a 118 metres (387 ft) tall skyscraper in the eastern part of the London financial district Canary Wharf. It was built in 2014 and has 23 storeys.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "Belarus participated in the Eurovision Song Contest 2014 with the song \"Cheesecake\" written by Yuriy Vashchuk and Dmitry Novik. The song was performed by Teo, which is the artistic name of", "answer": "singer"}
{"question": "United Nations Security Council Resolution 2167, concerning the critical role of regional cooperation in International Peacekeeping and Security was adopted unanimously on 28 July 2014. The resolution originated through a debate", "answer": "initiated"}
{"question": "The FATCA agreement is an international agreement signed between Canada and the United States that allows the implementation of the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act (an Act of the U.S. Congress)", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Separate men's and women's Wheelchair Basketball World Championship tournaments were held in 2014. The women's tournament was held at the Mattamy Athletic Centre in Toronto, Canada between 20 and 28 June", "answer": "2014."}
{"question": "The state visit of Michael D. Higgins to the United Kingdom occurred on 7 April 2014. It was the first state visit of a President of Ireland to the United Kingdom.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "The Abkhazian Revolution took place in 2014, when President Aleksandr Ankvab resigned after hundreds of demonstrators stormed his office. After mass protests in the capital Sukhumi and the occupation of his", "answer": "office"}
{"question": "The 2014 Kremlin Cup was a tennis tournament played on indoor hard courts. It was the 25th edition of the Kremlin Cup for the men (19th edition for the women) and", "answer": "part"}
{"question": "A long series of criminal investigations have occurred in Brazil associated with Operation Car Wash. The first investigation was launched in March 2014, and is now known as phase 1 of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 37th National Film Awards, presented by Ministry of Information, Bangladesh to felicitate the best of Bangladeshi Cinema released in 2012. Prime Minister gave Awards to the hand of award winner", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "In 2014, an outbreak of Ebola virus disease in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) occurred. Genome sequencing has shown that this outbreak was not related to the 2014–15 West", "answer": "Africa"}
{"question": "Hurricane Ana was the second tropical cyclone in 2014 to threaten the U.S. state of Hawaii with a direct hit, after Iselle in August. The twenty-first named storm and fifteenth hurricane", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "G 1/12 is a decision issued on 30 April 2014 by the Enlarged Board of Appeal of the European Patent Office (EPO), holding that an appellant's identity in a notice of", "answer": "appeal"}
{"question": "The 27th European Film Awards were presented on 13 December 2014 in Riga, Latvia. The winners were selected by more than 2,500 members of the European Film Academy. Nominations for the", "answer": "People's"}
{"question": "The Trojan Horse scandal, also known as \"Operation Trojan Horse\" or the Trojan Horse affair, involves claims of an alleged conspiracy to introduce an \"Islamist\" or \"Salafist\" ethos into several schools", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The War of 1812 Monument, officially titled Triumph Through Diversity (Triomphe grâce à la diversité in French), is a bronze and stone memorial, located at Parliament Hill in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada,", "answer": "Canada's"}
{"question": "2014–2016 Croatian war veterans tent protest was 555 days long war veterans protest, often dubbed in Croatia as The Tenters (Croatian: šatoraši). The protests were initially aimed against Ministry of Croatian", "answer": "Veterans"}
{"question": "The October 2014 Nicaragua earthquake occurred at 21:51 local time with a moment magnitude of 7.3 off the coast of Nicaragua, Honduras and El Salvador. The shock resulted in four deaths", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The Rotherham child sexual exploitation scandal consists of the organised child sexual abuse that occurred in the town of Rotherham, South Yorkshire, Northern England from the late 1980s until the 2010s", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The war on terror, officially the Global War on Terrorism (GWOT), is a global counterterrorism military campaign initiated by the United States following the September 11 attacks and is also the", "answer": "most"}
{"question": "The case of Ashya King concerns a boy named Ashya King, who had a brain tumour. His parents, Brett and Naghemeh King, took their son out of Southampton General Hospital (England)", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Between 13 and 18 May 2014 a low-pressure cyclone designated Tamara and Yvette affected a large area of Southeastern and Central Europe, causing floods and landslides. Serbia and Bosnia and Herzegovina", "answer": "suffered"}
{"question": "Georgia joined the war in Afghanistan in 2004 and the country had become the largest non-NATO and the largest per capita troop contributor to the International Security Assistance Force in Afghanistan", "answer": "by"}
{"question": "The World Scrabble Championship 2014, renamed by Mattel to Scrabble Champions Tournament in 2013, was held at the ExCeL London Exhibition and Convention Centre, London in November 2014. It was the", "answer": "first"}
{"question": "The 2014 UEC European Track Championships was the fifth edition of the elite UEC European Track Championships in track cycling and took place at the Vélodrome Amédée Détraux in Baie-Mahault, Guadeloupe,", "answer": "France,"}
{"question": "Spectra is the name of a series of art installations by Ryoji Ikeda which use intense white light as a sculptural material. The most recent presentation of spectra was in Hobart,", "answer": "Tasmania,"}
{"question": "Following the simultaneous federal elections and regional elections of 25 May 2014, negotiations started to form a new Federal Government as well as new regional governments: a Flemish, Walloon, French Community", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The Lenborough Hoard is a hoard of more than 5,000 late Anglo-Saxon silver coins, dating to the eleventh century, that was found at Lenborough in Buckinghamshire, England in 2014. It is", "answer": "believed"}
{"question": "The 2014 Wales Summit of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) was a meeting of the heads of state and heads of government of the NATO countries, held in Newport, Wales", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The Anti-Social Behaviour, Crime and Policing Act 2014 (c. 12) is an Act of the Parliament of the United Kingdom which consolidated and expanded law enforcement powers in addressing anti-social behaviour.", "answer": "One"}
{"question": "The 13N was a Cacerolazo against President Cristina Fernández de Kirchner that took place in Argentina on November 13, 2014. It was organized by social networks. The people in the demonstration", "answer": "protested"}
{"question": "The 2014 Toronto FC season was the eighth season in club history. During the off-season, Toronto FC agreed to a one-year partnership with USL outfit Wilmington Hammerheads. Jackson, Justin Morrow, Dwayne", "answer": "De"}
{"question": "The Oulu child murders is a Finnish murder case, referring to the discovery of the bodies of five infants in the basement of an apartment building in Oulu, on June 3,", "answer": "2014."}
{"question": "The 2014 United Nations Security Council election was held on 16 October 2014 during the 69th session of the United Nations General Assembly, held at United Nations Headquarters in New York", "answer": "City."}
{"question": "On February 3, 2014, 15-year-old high school student Sergey Gordeyev (Russian: Сергей Гордеев; also spelled Sergei Gordeev) opened fire at School No. 263 in Otradnoye District, Moscow, Russia, killing a teacher.", "answer": "Gordeyev"}
{"question": "The 2014–15 season was Galatasaray's 111th in existence and 57th consecutive season in the Süper Lig. The club were aiming for an unprecedented twentieth league title, after finishing in second place", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The Constitution of the Arab Republic of Egypt is the fundamental law of Egypt. The Egyptian Constitution of 2014 was passed in a referendum in January 2014. The constitution took effect", "answer": "after"}
{"question": "Blood Swept Lands and Seas of Red was a public art installation created in the moat of the Tower of London, England, between July and November 2014. It commemorated the centenary", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "From March 2012 to May 2014, the Salvadoran government, the Catholic Church, and the country's two largest criminal gangs, Mara Salvatrucha (MS-13) and the 18th Street gang (Barrio 18), came to", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "Malaysia Airlines Flight 17 (MH17/MAS17) was a scheduled passenger flight from Amsterdam to Kuala Lumpur that was shot down by Russian-controlled forces on 17 July 2014, while flying over eastern Ukraine.", "answer": "All"}
{"question": "All Star Extravaganza VI is a professional wrestling pay-per-view event produced by Ring of Honor (ROH). It took place on September 6, 2014, at the Mattamy Athletic Center in Toronto, Ontario,", "answer": "Canada."}
{"question": "Declared in June 2014, the West and Central African cholera outbreak as of January 25, 2015 claimed 1,683 registered deaths and over 91,361 reported cases with a reported case fatality rate", "answer": "(CFR)"}
{"question": "The 1st ceremony of the Feroz Awards was held at the Cine Callao in Madrid, on January 27, 2014. It was hosted by actress Alexandra Jiménez and aired on national TV", "answer": "through"}
{"question": "The 2014 Honda Indy Toronto was a Canadian open wheel motor race, held as the thirteenth and fourteenth rounds of the 2014 IndyCar Series season. It was the 28th annual edition", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "A terrorist ramming attack occurred on 4 August 2014, when a man drove an excavator type of tractor out of a construction site, injuring several pedestrians and killing one man before", "answer": "ramming"}
{"question": "The II CELAC summit or 2014 CELAC summit was the second ordinary heads of state summit of the Community of Latin American and Caribbean States. It was held on 28 and", "answer": "29"}
{"question": "The 2014 Sundarbans oil spill was an oil spill that occurred on 9 December 2014 at the Shela River in Sundarbans, Bangladesh, a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The spill occurred when", "answer": "an"}
{"question": "The 2014–2015 eruption of Fogo began on 23 November 2014, continuing until 8 February 2015. It was the first eruption of Pico do Fogo in 19 years, and the longest since", "answer": "its"}
{"question": "On 13 March 2014, an AgustaWestland AW139 helicopter of Haughey Air crashed shortly after taking off at night in fog from Gillingham, Norfolk, United Kingdom, killing all four people on board.", "answer": "Among"}
{"question": "Opération Chammal is a French military operation in Iraq and Syria launched to help curtail the expansion of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant and to support the Iraqi", "answer": "Army."}
{"question": "The 2014 National People's Congress (formally, the Second Session of the 12th National People's Congress) held its annual meeting in March 2014 at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing,", "answer": "China."}
{"question": "On the morning of 18 November 2014, two Palestinian men from Jerusalem entered Kehilat Bnei Torah synagogue, in the Har Nof neighborhood of Jerusalem, and attacked the praying congregants with axes,", "answer": "knives,"}
{"question": "Karen Petrosyan v. Azerbaijan was an international human rights case regarding the rights of Artush Petrosyan and his son Karen Petrosyan – an Armenian national from Chinari village, Tavush province of", "answer": "Armenia,"}
{"question": "On 5 May 2014, a yacht and a dinghy, both overcrowded and carrying migrants destined for Greece, capsized about four nautical miles off the coast of the Greek island of Samos,", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "A bronze statue of the British singer Amy Winehouse is located in the Stables Market in Camden Town, in north London. Sculpted by Scott Eaton, it was unveiled in 2014, three", "answer": "years"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Bahrain in November 2014 to elect the forty members of the Council of Representatives. The first round of voting took place on 22 November, with a", "answer": "second"}
{"question": "Oslo is a discothèque, bar and food venue located in Hackney Central, East London. It is the first club to open in that area of Hackney. Notable musicians that played in", "answer": "it"}
{"question": "The 2014 Iquique earthquake struck off the coast of Chile on 1 April, with a moment magnitude of 8.2, at 20:46 local time (23:46 UTC). The epicenter of the earthquake was", "answer": "approximately"}
{"question": "The 2014 Gaza Valley airstrike was a friendly fire incident that took place in Zabul Province, Afghanistan on 9 June 2014 when five U.S. troops and one Afghan interpreter were killed", "answer": "when"}
{"question": "The blockade of the Gaza Strip is the ongoing land, air, and sea blockade of the Gaza Strip imposed by Israel and Egypt temporarily in 2005–2006 and permanently from 2007 onwards,", "answer": "following"}
{"question": "On 28 April 2014, 61-year-old teacher Ann Maguire (5 April 1953 – 28 April 2014) was stabbed to death while teaching a Spanish lesson at Corpus Christi Catholic College in Halton", "answer": "Moor,"}
{"question": "The Thévenoud Law is a law by the Government of France that requires all chauffeurs to hold professional licenses, among other restrictions.The law was introduced in October 2014 by its namesake,", "answer": "Thomas"}
{"question": "The 72nd World Science Fiction Convention (Worldcon), also known as Loncon 3, was held on 14–18 August 2014 at the ExCeL London in London, United Kingdom.The convention committee was co-chaired by", "answer": "Alice"}
{"question": "The 2014 Laurence Olivier Awards was held on Sunday 13 April 2014 at the Royal Opera House, London. The awards were presented by Gemma Arterton and Stephen Mangan. The highlights programme", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "On 5 November 2014, in a terrorist ramming attack, a Hamas operative deliberately drove a van at high speed into a crowd of people waiting at the Shimon HaTzadik light rail", "answer": "station"}
{"question": "The 2014 Toronto municipal election was held on October 27, 2014, to elect a mayor and 44 city councillors in Toronto, Ontario, Canada. In addition, school trustees were elected to the", "answer": "Toronto"}
{"question": "A constitutional referendum was held in Egypt on 14 and 15 January 2014 and with Egyptians abroad voting between 8 and 12 January. The new constitution was approved by 98.1% of", "answer": "voters."}
{"question": "The Istanbul mayoral elections of 2014 were held on 30 March 2014, as part of the local elections taking place throughout Turkey on the same day. The Metropolitan Mayor of Istanbul", "answer": "as"}
{"question": "Marius (6 February 2012 – 9 February 2014) was a male giraffe living at Copenhagen Zoo. Though healthy, he was genetically unsuitable for future captive breeding, as his genes were over-represented", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The Normandy Format (French: Format Normandie), also known as the Normandy contact group, is a grouping of states who met in an effort to resolve the war in Donbas and the", "answer": "wider"}
{"question": "The third edition of the Champs-Élysées Film Festival was held from 11 to 17 June 2014, with actors Jacqueline Bisset and Bertrand Tavernier as Honorary Presidents and Keanu Reeves, Agnès Varda,", "answer": "Whit"}
{"question": "On 22 October 2014, a Palestinian rammed his car into a crowd of people waiting at the Ammunition Hill light rail station in the Sheikh Jarrah neighbourhood in East Jerusalem. The", "answer": "attack"}
{"question": "MS Norman Atlantic was a roll-on/roll-off passenger (ROPAX) ferry owned by the Italian ferry company Visemar di Navigazione. The ferry was chartered by ANEK Lines from December 2014. On 28 December", "answer": "2014,"}
{"question": "A long series of criminal investigations have occurred in Brazil associated with Operation Car Wash, since the first one began in March 2014. These investigations are considered offshoots of the original", "answer": "phased"}
{"question": "The Qingdao International Horticultural Exposition 2014 (Chinese: 2014青岛世界园艺博览会) is a horticultural exhibition recognised by the International Association of Horticultural Producers (as AIPH class A2/B1) in Qingdao, China. It is being held", "answer": "from"}
{"question": "The 2014 Belgian Cup Final, named Cofidis Cup after the sponsor, was the 59th Belgian Cup final and took place on 22 March 2014 between Lokeren and Zulte Waregem. It was", "answer": "won"}
{"question": "The 64th annual Berlin International Film Festival was held from 6 to 16 February 2014. Wes Anderson's film The Grand Budapest Hotel opened the festival. British film director Ken Loach was", "answer": "presented"}
{"question": "The 2014 by-election for the House of Commons constituency of Clacton in Essex, England, took place on 9 October 2014. The by-election was triggered by the Conservative MP for Clacton, Douglas", "answer": "Carswell,"}
{"question": "Art Buff is a graffiti artwork by Banksy which was created in Folkestone in 2014, Banksy announcing it as \"part of the Folkestone triennial. Kind of\". The work depicts a woman", "answer": "wearing"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Guam on November 4, 2014. Voters elected the governor, legislature, and territory's delegate to the United States House of Representatives. The Democratic and Republican primary elections", "answer": "were"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Fiji on 17 September 2014 to select the 50 members of Parliament. The FijiFirst party led by Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama won a landslide victory, winning", "answer": "32"}
{"question": "The 2013–2014 Bulgarian protests against the Oresharski cabinet was a series of demonstrations that were held in Bulgaria, mainly in the capital Sofia, against the left-wing coalition cabinet of Oresharski (coalition", "answer": "between"}
{"question": "The 2014 Australian federal budget was the federal budget to fund government services and operations for the 2014/15 financial year. The 2014 budget was the first delivered by the Abbott government,", "answer": "since"}
{"question": "On 20 March 2014, Taliban militants carried out a mass shooting in the restaurant of the Kabul Serena Hotel, in Kabul, Afghanistan. The shooting, which took place in a hotel popular", "answer": "with"}
{"question": "General elections were due to be held in Sark on 10 December 2014. However, only 16 candidates nominated for the 16 seats in the Chief Pleas, meaning that all were elected", "answer": "unopposed,"}
{"question": "Euromaidan (; Ukrainian: Євромайдан, romanized: Yevromaidan, lit. 'Euro Square', IPA: [jeu̯romɐjˈdɑn]), or the Maidan Uprising, was a wave of demonstrations and civil unrest in Ukraine, which began on 21 November 2013", "answer": "with"}
{"question": "G 1/11 is a decision issued on 19 March 2014 by the Enlarged Board of Appeal of the European Patent Office (EPO), holding that a Technical Board of Appeal rather than", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2014 American immigration crisis was a surge in unaccompanied children and women from the Northern Triangle of Central America (NTCA) seeking entrance to the United States in 2014. According to", "answer": "U.S."}
{"question": "On 11 February 2014, a C-130 Hercules military transport aircraft of the Algerian Air Force, carrying 74 passengers and 4 crew members, crashed into Djebel Fertas mountain near Aïn Kercha, Algeria.", "answer": "Only"}
{"question": "The 2014 UK Music Video Awards were held on 10 November 2014 at the Queen Elizabeth Hall in Southbank Centre, London and was hosted by Adam Buxton to recognise the best", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "General elections were held in the Cook Islands on 9 July 2014, determining the membership of the 14th Cook Islands Parliament. The Cook Islands Party (CIP) initially appeared to have retained", "answer": "its"}
{"question": "The Practice of the 'One Country, Two Systems' Policy in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (Chinese: 「一國兩制」在香港特別行政區的實踐) is a white paper issued by the Information Office of the State Council", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Armenia participated in the Junior Eurovision Song Contest 2014 which took place on 15 November 2014, in Marsa, Malta. The Armenian broadcaster Armenia 1 (ARMTV) was responsible for organising their entry", "answer": "for"}
{"question": "Virunga is a 2014 British documentary film directed by Orlando von Einsiedel. It focuses on the conservation work of park rangers within the Congo's Virunga National Park during the rise of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Battle for Yasynuvata — was a series of battles in the summer of 2014 for the village of Yasynuvata in Donbas. Control over Yasynuvata was crucial in controlling the routes of", "answer": "communication"}
{"question": "The 4th Magritte Awards ceremony, presented by the Académie André Delvaux, honored the best films of 2013 in Belgium and took place on 1 February 2014, at the Square in the", "answer": "historic"}
{"question": "The Willis Resilience Expedition was a scientific and exploratory program that took place in Antarctica from November 2013 to January 2014, with the goal of a better understanding of changes in", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Occupy Ghana also known as Occupy Flagstaff House is a protest or pressure movement in Ghana which started online as #occupyflagstaffhouse or #occupyflagstaff, and generated into an offline protest. On July", "answer": "1,"}
{"question": "The Hotesur scandal took place in Argentina in 2014. Hotesur is a firm that administers the hotels in El Calafate that belong to Cristina Fernández de Kirchner and her family. Initially,", "answer": "it"}
{"question": "Miss Belgium 2014 was the 46th edition of the Miss Belgium held on January 11, 2014 at the Plopsaland Theater in De Panne, Belgium. The winner, Laurence Langen from Limburg, was", "answer": "crowned"}
{"question": "The deaths of Simone Camilli and Ali Shehda Abu Afash occurred while the two journalists were reporting on the 2014 Israel–Gaza conflict. Simone Camilli (c. 1979 – 13 August 2014), an", "answer": "Italian,"}
{"question": "The 2014 Balkan Athletics Indoor Championships was the 19th edition of the annual indoor track and field competition for athletes from the Balkans, organised by Balkan Athletics. It was held on", "answer": "22"}
{"question": "Conference of Western Balkan States was a 28 August 2014 conference of heads of states and governments of Western Balkans region initiated by German chancellor Angela Merkel. An idea for organization", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2013–2014 Thai political crisis was a period of political instability in Thailand. Anti-government protests took place between November 2013 and May 2014, organised by the People's Democratic Reform Committee (PDRC),", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "Brit Awards 2014 was held on 19 February 2014. It was the 34th edition of the British Phonographic Industry's annual pop Brit Awards. The awards ceremony was held at The O2", "answer": "Arena"}
{"question": "On 18 April 2014, a group of sixteen Chinese citizens, later identified as ethnic Uyghurs, engaged in a shootout with Vietnamese border guards after seizing their guns as they were being", "answer": "detained"}
{"question": "The 2013–14 North American winter was one of the most significant for the United States, due in part to the breakdown of the polar vortex in November 2013, which allowed very", "answer": "cold"}
{"question": "The Falkland Islands was represented at the 2014 Commonwealth Games in Glasgow by 25 athletes across three sports, badminton, shooting, and lawn bowls, the largest ever Falkland Islands squad to be", "answer": "sent"}
{"question": "Japanese whaling, in terms of active hunting of whales, is estimated by the Japan Whaling Association to have begun around the 12th century. However, Japanese whaling on an industrial scale began", "answer": "around"}
{"question": "The Great Fire of Valparaíso (Spanish: Gran Incendio de Valparaíso) started on 12 April 2014 at 16:40 local time (19:40 UTC), in the hills of the city of Valparaíso, Chile. The", "answer": "wildfire"}
{"question": "The 2014 protests in Brazil, also known as There won't be a Cup or Fifa go home were public demonstrations in several Brazilian cities in response to the 2014 FIFA World", "answer": "Cup"}
{"question": "The Battle of Shuja'iyya occurred between the Israel Defense Forces and the Izz ad-Din al-Qassam Brigades on 20 July 2014 during 2014 Israel–Gaza conflict in the Shuja'iyya neighborhood of Gaza City,", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Bosnia and Herzegovina on 12 October 2014. They decided the makeup of Bosnia and Herzegovina's Presidency as well as national, entity, and cantonal governments. Voter turnout", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "The 2013–2016 epidemic of Ebola virus disease, centered in Western Africa, was the most widespread outbreak of the disease in history. It caused major loss of life and socioeconomic disruption in", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Alexandre-Ferdinand Nguendet (born 23 May 1972) is a Central African politician who served as President of the National Transitional Council of the Central African Republic from 2013 to 2016. He briefly", "answer": "served"}
{"question": "On 18 March 2014, Russian president Vladimir Putin gave a speech to both chambers of the Federal Assembly of the Russian Federation in connection with the request for admission by the", "answer": "Crimean"}
{"question": "In 2014, a series of groundbreaking diplomatic meetings was held between Wang Yu-chi, in his official capacity as the Minister of the Mainland Affairs Council (MAC) of the Republic of China", "answer": "(ROC),"}
{"question": "Ceiliúradh was a celebration of Irish culture that took place in the Royal Albert Hall on 10 April 2014, to mark the state visit to London of Irish President Michael D.", "answer": "Higgins."}
{"question": "Marin Draganja and Nikola Mektić were the defending champions but only Nikola Mektić returned, partnering Goran Tošić, but lost in the first round to Dino Marcan and Antonio Šančić. Dino Marcan", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The third competition weekend of the 2014–15 ISU Speed Skating World Cup will be held in Sportforum Hohenschönhausen in Berlin, Germany, from Friday, 5 December, until Sunday, 7 December 2014.Artur Waś", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The Batwa–Luba clashes were a series of clashes in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) between the Pygmy Batwa people, and the Luba people that began in 2013 and ended", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Anti-government protests (Khmer: បាតុកម្មប្រឆាំងរាជរដ្ឋាភិបាល) were a series of protests in Cambodia from July 2013 to July 2014. Popular demonstrations in Phnom Penh took place against the government of Prime Minister Hun", "answer": "Sen,"}
{"question": "BugSat 1 (nickname Tita) is an Argentine microsatellite launched on 19 June 2014. The satellite is built in flattened box shape, optimized for piggy-back launch. All instruments are powered by solar", "answer": "cells"}
{"question": "Tbilisi, I Love You (Georgian: თბილისი, მიყვარხარ Tbilisi, miq’varkhar) is a 2014 anthology film starring an ensemble cast of actors of various nationalities and part of Emmanuel Benbihy’s Cities Of Love", "answer": "franchise"}
{"question": "The Cuban thaw (Spanish: Deshielo cubano) was the normalization of Cuba–United States relations that began in December 2014 ending a 54-year stretch of hostility between the nations. In March 2016, Barack", "answer": "Obama"}
{"question": "A rescue occurred at Riesending cave between 8–19 June 2014, in Bavaria, Germany, after a speleologist, who had been exploring the cave in a group of three, suffered a traumatic brain", "answer": "injury"}
{"question": "The 2013–2014 chikungunya outbreak represented the first recorded outbreak of the disease outside of tropical Africa and Asia. In December 2013, the first locally transmitted case of chikungunya in the Americas", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "The 2014 Nippon Professional Baseball (NPB) Draft was held on October 23, 2014, for the 50th time at the Grand Prince Hotel Takanawa to assign amateur baseball players to the NPB.", "answer": "It"}
{"question": "The following addresses the events in Northern Afghanistan between April 2009 and 2014. While this part of the country had long been relatively peaceful compared to the all-out war zones of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "March in March refers to a series of marches which were held around Australia on 15–16 March 2014, and in Canberra, the national capital, on 17 March 2014, a parliamentary sitting", "answer": "day."}
{"question": "The 2014 Berlin Marathon was the 41st edition of the Berlin Marathon. The marathon took place in Berlin, Germany, on 28 September 2014 and was the fourth World Marathon Majors race", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Concluding observations on the second periodic report of the Holy See was a 2014 report issued by the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights, regarding the handling", "answer": "by"}
{"question": "The 2014 Burkina Faso uprising was a series of demonstrations and riots in Burkina Faso in October 2014 that quickly spread to multiple cities. They began in response to attempts at", "answer": "changing"}
{"question": "The Western Antarctic Ice Sheet (WAIS) is the segment of the continental ice sheet that covers West Antarctica, the portion of Antarctica on the side of the Transantarctic Mountains that lies", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Blockupy is a movement protesting against austerity. The Blockupy alliance includes trade unions and Germany's Linkspartei.Representing grass-roots critics of supranational financial institutions such as the “troika”: the European Commission (EC), European", "answer": "Central"}
{"question": "Lights Out was an event on 4 August 2014 in the United Kingdom to commemorate the centenary of the start of World War I. It was inspired by the words of", "answer": "Sir"}
{"question": "Dormaalocyon (\"dog from Dormaal\") is an extinct genus of placental mammals from clade Carnivoraformes, that lived in Europe during early Eocene. Type species, Dormaalocyon latouri was discovered when fossils were unearthed", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The 23rd Actors and Actresses Union Awards ceremony was held on 10 March 2014 at the Teatro Coliseum in Madrid. The gala was hosted by Llum Barrera and Secun de la", "answer": "Rosa.In"}
{"question": "The 2014 Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe was a horse race held at Longchamp on Sunday, 5 October 2014. It was the 93rd running of the Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "Berkin Elvan (5 January 1999 – 11 March 2014) was a 15-year-old boy who was hit on the head by a tear-gas canister fired by a police officer in Istanbul during", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2014 Balkans Cup was a rugby league football tournament that was held in Serbia between 17 October and 19 October. The winner won the inaugural Balkans Cup Trophy.Four teams competed", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Operation Baawar (Pashto for assurance), was a major Afghan-led offensive in Afghanistan west of the city of Kandahar. The operation took place primarily in a sector known as the Horn of", "answer": "Panjwaii."}
{"question": "The 2014–15 Aruban Division di Honor season is the 54th season of top-tier football in Aruba. It began on 10 October 2014. Britannia are the reigning champions, coming off their fourth", "answer": "league"}
{"question": "The 2014 Toronto Mayoral Election took place on October 27, 2014. Incumbent Mayor Rob Ford initially ran for re-election, but dropped out after being diagnosed with a tumour - instead running", "answer": "for"}
{"question": "Mister World 2014 was the 8th edition of the Mister World competition. It was held at The Riviera International Conference Centre in Torbay, Devon, England on June 15, 2014. Francisco Javier", "answer": "Escobar"}
{"question": "Aljaž Bedene was the defending champion, and returned to defend his title but lost to Viktor Troicki in the quarterfinals. Viktor Troicki won the title by defeating Albert Ramos 7–5, 4–6,", "answer": "7–5"}
{"question": "The Eurovision Song Contest 2014 was the 59th edition of the Eurovision Song Contest. It took place in Copenhagen, Denmark, following the country's victory at the 2013 contest with the song", "answer": "\"Only"}
